

ANSHU RANI

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

anshurani.github.io | +91-9457935682 | New Delhi, India | anshurani261194@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Highly motivated & dedicated Full Stack Developer with over 6 years of experience developing and optimizing user-focused websites & applications. Technical Proficient, Strong leadership & Problem-solving skills, collaborative team player, and versatile and flexible for new challenges.

Skills & Abilities

- TECHNICAL SKILLS
 - o Client-Side: Next JS, Vue, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS
 - o Server-Side: Ruby on Rails, Node JS, PostgreSQL, MySQL
 - o Development & Operations: GIT, Jenkins, Jira, Agile, Scrum
- PROBLEM-SOLVING
- ADAPTABILITY AND FLEXIBILITY
- LEADERSHIP SKILLS THAT INCLUDE TRAINING OF JUNIOR PROGRAMMERS
- PROACTIVE NATURE

Experience

DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE, MINISTRY OF LAW & JUSTICE

Web Developer - Consultant | July 2024 - Present

- Deputed at NRSC, ISRO to provide technical expertise for the maintenance and enhancement of the Nyaya Vikas Portal, which focuses on monitoring the physical infrastructure of district courts and judicial facilities across the country.
- Managing database backups and server maintenance to ensure smooth operations.
- Working on the design and development of Nyaya Vikas 3.0 using modern tech stacks like Next.js and Node.js.

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPMENT

June 2022 - June 2024

- Self-thinking and find the solution to solve the tasks. Communicate with the client to make it details.
- Database tables designing and migrating with Active Record and PostgreSQL.
- Used Docker to build containers and run Ruby on Rails on different environment.
- Creating Single-Page Applications with React that deliver a modern user experience.
- Worked with Active Record Classes from Rails Console for Database Programming.

RAILYATRI

Technology Specialist | Sep 2019 - Feb 2022

- Developed and maintained end-to-end responsive and user-friendly website pages using Ruby on Rails.
- Closely worked with SEO team to improve website's performance for better google ranking.
- With my flexible nature, I have learnt React and developed multiple pages for good user experience.
- Integrated third party services to the product for business growth.
- Trained and mentored new employees and interns on product knowledge and ruby on rails coding standards and best practices.

1MG TECHNOLOGIES

Back-end Developer | Feb 2019 - Sep 2019

- Design and Implemented Optimized RESTful APIs for the product.
- Monitored and troubleshoot website performance.
- Participated in peer-to-peer code reviews to follow best coding practice.
- Built database's table structures following architecture methodology
- Optimized Postgres queries for the heavy-load parts of the website, which improved API's response time.

SVASTH LIFE

Full-stack developer | Aug 2015 - Nov 2016

- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop effective solutions in timely manner.
- Hands on deployment and environment configuration.
- Troubleshoot, debug and improved existing applications with fixing issues.
- Wrote test cases to verify the functionalities of back-end component
- Built end-to-end features and RESTful APIs for the website using Ruby on Rails.
- Implemented third party tracking tools for better user experience.

AIRTIGHT NETWORKS

Developer Intern | Jan 2015 - Jul 2015

- Created an Instagram Authentication plugin which allowed guest users to access Wi-Fi after authentication using Instagram's OAuth2 Login APIs.
- Followed Agile Development methodology and scrum for the tasks.

Education

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, ALLAHABAD

Allahabad | B. Tech in Information Technology

Earned a 7.67 CGPA and completed relevant coursework in software development, database management, Operating system and software engineering.

Languages

- Hindi
- English